Guide to the Larry Goodell Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1954-2016; Series I; 8.67; (8 boxes)
  - Unsorted cards, letters, programs, 1976-1992 (Box 8)
  - Goodell, Larry, 1957-1990; (3 folders) (Box 8)
    Includes correspondence to/from publishers and poets concerning submitted writings, possible publications, poetry readings, and the Living Batch bookstore.
  - Somos Muse News newsletters, 1994-2003 (Box 8)
    SOMOS is the Society of the Muse of the Southwest, based in Taos, New Mexico.
  - Unidentified envelope addressed to Larry Goodell, 1974 (Box 8)
- Duende Press records, 1964-2010; Series II; 3.25; (3 boxes)
  Contains business records related to Duende Press--a publishing concern founded and run by Larry Goodell--including writings submitted for publication, documentation of events, and financial records. Poetry and other writings by can also be found in Series I, Correspondence and writings.
  Material within this series have been organized into three subseries: Business records, Submitted writings, and Production materials for Fervent Valley and Oriental and Blue Streak publications.
  - Business records, 1964-2001
    Contains financial and logistical documentation of Duende Press.
    - Business correspondence, 1966-1987 (Box 9)
    - Articles of incorporation, 1970 (Box 9)
    - Duende Press/Fervent Valley business letterhead, undated (Box 9)
    - Business correspondence and papers, 1964-1987 (Box 9)
    - Invoices and financial papers, 1967-2001; 4 (Box 9)
    - Receipts and rent notices for Larry Goodell, 1964-1965 (Box 9)
    - Distribution catalogs, 1982-1997; (3 folders) (Box 9)
      Includes catalogs and papers related to Duende Press's dealings with Book People.
    - Business grants, 1975-2006; (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - Invoices, 1971-1974 (Box 9)
    - Duende Press ISBN, 1974 (Box 9)
    - "Characters of the Sacred" notes, 1995 (Box 9)
      Includes papers related to Duende Press's publication of "Characters of the Sacred" by Bill Pearlman.
    - Orders, 1964-2008; (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - Duende Press catalog and ephemera, undated (Box 9)
    - Reviews and promotional materials, 1976-1996 (Box 9)
    - Duende Press tax papers, 1992 (Box 9)
    - Duende Press "to-do promo", 1995 (Box 9)
    - Rex-Rotary M4 Mimeograph instructions, undated (Box 9)
    - Mimeograph splotch art, 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Submitted writings, 1964-2010
    Contains poetry and other works sent to Duende Press for publication consideration.
    - Bayes, Ronald--History of the Turtle Book 4 (Duende, no. 10, 1965)--original cover art work by Signe Nelson (Box 10)
    - Crews, Judson--The Noose, A Retrospective: 4 Decades draft (Duende Press, 1980), (3 folders) (Box 10)
    - Crews, Judson--The Noose, A Retrospective: 4 Decades--paste-up, undated (Box 10)
    - Crews, Judson--The Noose, A Retrospective: 4 Decades--business, publicity, and assorted documentation, 1979-1982 (Box 10)
      - Dodd, William--Se Marier draft. (Duende Press, 1969) (Box 10)
    - Harris, Latif (William)--Poems/1965--special inscribed draft copy (Duende Press, 1965) (Box 10)
    - Kelly, Robert--"Lectiones" draft. (Duende, no. 7, 1965) (Box 10)
    - Goodell, Larry--"Writings from the Rio" draft, undated; (2 folders) (Box 10)
      "Writings From Rio" is an unpublished anthology of writers edited by Larry Goodell, originally scheduled to have been published by Duende Press in 1993.
    - Pearlman, Bill--Inzorbital (Duende Press, 1974)--correspondence and notes, 1975 (Box 10)
    - Pearlman, Bill--Inzorbital (Duende Press, 1974)--Jack Hirschman "Notation" draft, undated (Box 10)
    - Randall, Margaret--"Small Sounds from the Bass Fiddle" draft (Duende, no. 5, 1964) (Box 10)
    - Sky, Gino Clays--"The Ball Tournament Specialist" artwork, mockup, extra printed pages and, photographs (Duende Press, 1973) (Box 10)
    - Sky, Gino Clays--"The Ball Tournament Specialist" draft, undated (Box 10)
    - White shaman "controversy" documentation including correspondence with Jim Cody, Gerald Hobson, Gene Fowler, and Larry Goodell, 1975-2014 (Box 10)
    - Duende Press submitted writings, 1982-2001; (8 folders) (Box 10)
  - Production materials for Fervent Valley and Oriental Blue Streak publications, 1968-1974
    Contains mock-ups and drafts of publications created by Larry Goodell and published by Duende Press.
    - Fervent Valley, no. 1, spring 1972--draft, (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - Fervent Valley, no. 1, spring 1972--photography by Wayne Jones for back cover (Box 11)
    - Fervent Valley, no. 1, spring 1972--mock-up and notes (Box 11)
    - Fervent Valley--writings submitted for issue no. 2, undated (Box 11)
    - Fervent Valley, no. 3, spring 1973--draft (Box 11)
    - Fervent Valley, no.3, spring 1973--mock-up (Box 11)
    - Fervent Valley, no.3, spring 1973--paste-up (Box 11)
    - Fervent Valley, no.4, spring 1974--cover with complimentary copies list on verso (Box 11)
    - Oriental Blue Streak draft, 1968 (Box 11)
      Oriental Blue Streak was a one-off magazine edited by Larry Goodell.
- Berkeley and Vancouver Poetry Conference papers, 1963-1965; Series III; 1.08; (1 box)
  Contains information sheet, notes, correspondence (incoming and outgoing), photographs, clippings and ephemera related to the Larry Goodell's experiences at the Berkeley Poetry Conference (1965) and the Vancouver Poetry Conference (1963). The materials include writings from poetry workshop participants, Goodell's personal journal and photographs, and conference programs.
  Material within this series maintains the original organization found at time of acquisition.
  - Berkeley Poetry Conference, July 21-24, 1965--schedules and information sheet (Box 12)
  - Vancouver Poetry Conference (English 410), July-August 1963--typescripts handed out to participants (2 folders) (Box 12)
  - Vancouver Poetry Conference (English 410), July-August 1963--spiral-bound journal of LG's Vancouver trip, July-October 1963 (Box 12)
  - Vancouver Poetry Conference (English 410), July-August 1963--correspondence, incl. Warren Tallman (Box 12)
  - Larry Goodell personal photographs, undated; (2 folders) (Box 12)
- Flyers for poetry events, 1978-2010; Series IV; 3.08; (2 boxes)
  Contains documentation related to events that Larry Goodell organized, attended, or in which he participated. The materials include flyers, clippings, and ephemera, predominantly related to poetry readings in New Mexico and the Southwestern United States.
  - Events with Larry Goodell, 1979-2005; (5 folders) (Box 12)
  - Events with which Larry Goodell was associated, 1980-1997 (Box 12)
  - The Central Torta Poetry series, 1980 (Box 12)
  - Downtown Center for the Arts, incl. Experimental Performance Festival, 1981 and Albuquerque United Artists (Box 12)
  - Downtown Saturday Night, May-July 1978 (Box 12)
  - Downtown Saturday Night, 1979 (Box 12)
  - Duende Poetry Series, 2006-2010 (Box 12)
  - Living Batch Bookstore flyer + Living Batch newsletter, undated (Box 12)
  - National Poetry Week in Santa Fe, 1990 (Box 12)
  - Silva's Saloon, Bernalillo, N. M., 1995 (Box 12)
  - Taos Poetry Circus/World Poetry Bout Association, undated (Box 12)
  - Zocalo Theatre, Bernalillo, NM, 1982-1999; (3 folders) (Box 12)
  - Poetry readings and other assorted events, 1988-1992 (Box 12)
  - Event posters, (2 folders) (Box 18 (Oversize))
- Personal papers, 1968-2005; Series V; 4.58; (4 boxes)
  Contains materials related to Larry Goodell's life and work as a poet, teacher and performer. Materials include annotated galley proofs of two books by Goodell, along with student writings from poetry workshops led by Goodell, photographs, documentation of performances by Goodell, and various ephemera.
  - Writings, 1978-1994
    - E. Pod #3 Oct. 1978 (Box 12)
    - Educational Babble (notes), undated (Box 12)
    - "Firecracker Soup" galley and notes, undated (Box 8)
    - "Here On Earth" draft and notes, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Small press ephemera, 1968-2005; (2 folders) (Box 12)
  - Internet screenshot images of Larry Goodell music album packaging, undated (Box 12)
  - Handmade book documenting :June 9-21st 1964--Ron and Fred Franklyn visit reading Creeley Fest, undated (Box 12)
  - Photographs by Wayne Jones--Larry Goodell reading "The Staff of Ometeotl" at the Thunderbird Bar, Placitas, NM, circa 1974 (Box 12)
  - Photographs by Bob Christensen--Larry Goodell "Bowl of Ometeol" poem sequence performance at Thunderbird Bar, Placitas, NM, 1975 (Box 12)
  - Mel Buffington photographs of Larry Goodell, undated (Box 12)
  - "Serious Art" flyer + Lenore Goodell photographs of Larry Goodell, undated (Box 12)
  - Harry Morris photographs of Larry Goodell, undated (Box 12)
    Annoatations indicate photographs used for Morris's illustrations to John Shirley's "Heatseeker".
  - Photographs of performance by Eve Sonneman, undated (Box 12)
  - UCSD reunion promotional materials, undated (Box 12)
  - Larry Goodell's personal photographs, undated; (2 folders) (Box 12)
  - Workshop/student publications with accompanying notes for some volumes, undated; (12 folders) (Box 13)
  - Workshop/student publication, undated (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Student writings, undated (Box 14)
  - Larry Goodell address cards, undated (Box 14)
  - Newspaper clipping, undated (Box 18 (Oversize))
- Audiovisual materials, 1986-2008; Series VI; 1.75; (3 boxes)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Boxes 15-16 (digital media): Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Box 17 (audiocassette): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Organized into two subseries: Poetry readings and Music and performance recordings.
  Contains electronic and analog media including audio recordings of poetry readings and musical performances by Larry Goodell and others.
  - Poetry reading recordings, 1980-2011, undated
    Contains audio recordings of poetry readings, performed primarily in the Albuquerque, New Mexico region.
    Arranged alphabetically by poet's last name.
    - Amy Beeder and Stefi Weisburd read at Acequia Booksellers, 2010; 1 (Box 15)
    - Dave Benedetti Reads, 2007; 1 (Box 15)
    - Mei-mei Berssenbrugge and Jonathan Skinner read at Acequia Booksellers, 2011; 1 (Box 15)
    - Jim Bishop Reads, 2006; 1 (Box 15)
    - Jim Bishop reads from "Mother Tongue", 1983; 1 (Box 15)
    - Michael Boughn reads from "Cosmographia", 2009; 1 (Box 15)
    - Gary Brower Reads, 2007; 1 (Box 15)
    - John Clarke and Charles Keil in performance--Buffalo, 1984-1985, undated; 1 (Box 15)
    - Wayne Crawford Reads, 2009; 1 (Box 15)
    - Craig Dworkin and Mary Rising Higgins read in Albuquerque, 2006; 1 (Box 15)
    - David Empfield reads from "The Horse Opera" and other works, 2002; 1 (Box 15)
    - David Empfield reads from "Love in the KGB", 2008; 1 (Box 15)
    - Gene Frumkin Reads, 2005; 1 (Box 15)
    - Drum Hadley's "Voice of the Badlands", circa 2006; 12 (Box 15)
    - Burt Hatlen--New Poems, 2006; 1 (Box 15)
    - Mary Rising Higgins Reads, 2005; 1 (Box 15)
    - Reading at the Harwood Art Center--Mary Rising Higgins and others, 2006; 1 (Box 15)
    - Bruce Holsapple--Skull of Caves, 2004-2005; 1 (Box 15)
    - Bruce Holsapple reads from "Vanishing Act", 2005; 1 (Box 15)
    - Bruce Holsapple and Randy Prus, circa 1989; 1 (Box 15)
    - Albert Huffstickler Reads, undated; 1 (Box 15)
    - George Kalamaras and Alvaro Cardona-Hine, 2010; 1 (Box 15)
    - James Koller, 2004; 1 (Box 15)
    - Jeffrey Lee and David Abel read at Acequia Booksellers, 2007; 1 (Box 15)
    - Joan Logghe Reads, 2008; 1 (Box 15)
    - John Macker reads at Acequia Booksellers, 2008; 1 (Box 15)
    - Amalio Madueno and Alvaro Cardona-Hine read at Anasazi Fields Winery, 2011; 1 (Box 15)
    - Chico Martin Reads, 2006; 1 (Box 15)
    - Howard McCord Reads, 2011; 1 (Box 15)
    - Howard McCord reads at Anasazi Fields Winery, 2011; 1 (Box 15)
    - Carol Moldaw reads at Acequia Booksellers, 2010; 1 (Box 15)
    - Todd Moore Reads, 2006; 1 (Box 15)
    - Todd Moore and Lawrence Welsh read at Acequia Booksellers, 2009; 1 (Box 15)
    - A. F. Moritz reads from "Here", 1980; 1 (Box 15)
    - Stanley Noyes Reads, 2010; 1 (Box 15)
    - V. B. Price reads at Acequia Booksellers, 2010; 1 (Box 15)
    - Margaret Randall Reads, 2008; 1 (Box 15)
    - Janet Rodney Reads, 2008; 1 (Box 15)
    - Michael Rothenberg and David Meltzer at the Outpost, 2007; 1 (Box 15)
    - Lee Sharkey reads from "A Darker, Sweeter Thing", 2008; 1 (Box 15)
    - Joseph Somoza Reads, 2009; 1 (Box 15)
    - Joseph Somoza reads at Placitas, 2005; 1 (Box 15)
    - Marilyn Stablein reads at Acequia Booksellers, 2010; 1 (Box 15)
    - Bill Sylvester Reads, 2006; 1 (Box 15)
    - Nathaniel Tarn Reads, 2008; 1 (Box 15)
    - Nathaniel Tarn reads at Acequia Booksellers, 2009; 1 (Box 15)
    - John Tritica reads his poetry, 2005; 1 (Box 15)
    - John Triteca reads at Acequia Booksellers, 2008; 1 (Box 15)
    - John Triteca reads "Fire in the New Year" and "Resonant Vocation", 2010; 1 (Box 15)
    - Anne Valley-Fox reads at Acequia Booksellers, 2010; 1 (Box 15)
    - Lawrence Welsh Reads, 2011; 1 (Box 15)
    - Keith Wilson reads from "Lion's Gate" Vols. 1-2, 2009; 2 (Box 16)
    - Keith Wilson Tribute at Anasazi Fields Winery, 2008; 1 (Box 16)
    - Mera Wolf and Todd Moore read at Acequia Booksellers, 2008; 1 (Box 16)
    - Timothy Wright reads "The Dust of Europe"--January 1980, undated; 1 (Box 16)
  - Music and performance recordings, 1986-2013
    - "Albuzerxque" compilations, 2000-2007; 10 (Box 16)
    - The Bubbadinos, 1999, 2001; 2 (Box 16)
    - The Line Has Shattered: Vancouver's Landmark 1963 Poetry Conference film, 2013; 1 (Box 16)
    - Mark Weber poetry and musical recordings, 1995-2007; 4 (Box 16)
    - The Mad New Mexican--Larry Goodell Songs 1981-1986, 1 (Box 17)